-==http://www.1000fr.com==- 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
福尔摩斯探案集
四签名
有个年轻漂亮的女人
There's a very pretty young woman
走过街来
crossing the street
我想她可能要到这
and I think she may be coming here.
顺便说一句 我大概看了一下
Incidentally, I have glanced over
你对我工作的最新记录
your latest account of my work.
怎么了
Oh yes.
坦白的讲 我并不赞同
Honestly I cannot congratulate you upon it.
侦探学是一门非常精确的科学
Detection is, or ought to be, an exact science.
应是观察后的推理
Observation deduction
要有冷静非感性的大脑研究它
a cold and unemotional subject.
你试图给它加上浪漫的色彩
You have attempted to tinge it with romanticism,
这就像把爱情故事
which has much the same effect
或是一场私奔
as if you worked a love-story or an
变成欧几里德的第五个几何命题一样
elopement into the fifth proposition of Euclid.
一点都不搭调
Who can match that?
有位年轻的女士要见你 福尔摩斯先生
There's a young lady to see you Mr. Holmes.
是Mary Morstan
It's Mary Morstan.
这名字我一点都没印象
I have no recollection of the name.
别走 医生 我可能需要你
Don't go Doctor, I may need you.
我没猜错
I was right.
谢谢
Thank you.
Morstan女士
Miss Morstan.
下午好
Good afternoon.
我今天来找你 福尔摩斯先生
I have come to you Mr. Holmes
是因为你曾为我的雇主
because you once enabled my employer,
Cecil Forrester夫人
Mrs. Cecil Forrester,
解决了一次小型家庭纠纷
to unravel a minor domestic complication.
她对你的善意和智慧
She was much impressed
印象深刻
with your kindness and skill.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想象不出 有什么比我现在的处境
I can hardly imagine anything more strange,
更加...奇怪
more utterly inexplicable,
或是更令人费解的了
than the situation in which I find myself.
说说案情吧
State your case.
抱歉 失陪了
You will, I am sure, excuse me.
你的朋友再坐会吧
If your friend would be good enough to remain,
也许还需要他的帮助
he might be of inestimable service to me.
好吧
Of course.
简单的说...
Briefly the facts are these.
我父亲是一名派驻到印度的军官
My father was an officer in an Indian regiment.
我母亲在我还很小的时候就去世了
My mother died when I was still quite a child
他不得不把我送回国内
and he was forced to send me home,
虽然国内已没有亲戚在了
despite the fact that I had no relatives here.
我被安排在爱丁堡
I was placed in a
一个舒适的寄宿学校读书
comfortable boarding establishment
我一直在那儿
at Edinburgh, and I remained there
呆到17岁才离开
until I was 1 7 years of age.
就在那年 我父亲...
In that same year my father,
那个团里资格最老的上尉
who was a senior captain of his regiment,
请了一年的假回家
obtained 12 months' leave and returned home.
他到达伦敦后 发电报给我说
He telegraphed to me from London to say
他已平安到达
that he had arrived all safe
让我马上到这来
and directed me to come down at once,
给了我他居住的 Langham旅馆的地址
giving the Langham Hotel as his address.
我记得他的电报里
His message, as I remember,
充满慈爱
was full of love and kindness.
一到伦敦
On reaching London
我就直接去了Langham旅店
I drove straight to the Langham Hotel
那儿的人告诉我说 确实有一位Morstan上尉住在这里
and was informed that Captain Morstan
但是他已经出去两天了
was staying there,
还没有回来
but that he had gone out the night before
and had not returned.
于是我等在那里
So I waited
一整天
all day
没有他的任何消息
without news of him.
那天夜里
And that night,
在旅馆经理的建议下
on the advice of the manager of the hotel,
我找了警察
I communicated with the police,
第二天又在各种报纸上
the next day we advertised
登了寻人启事
in all the newspapers.
可是一点结果都没有
Our inquiries led to no result
从那天到现在
from that day to this
没有任何关于
no word has ever been heard
我不幸父亲的消息
of my unfortunate father.
他这次回来本希望
He came home with his heart so full of hope
找个安静的地方
to find some peace,
享享清福
some comfort,
没想到...
and instead
什么时候失踪的?
The date?
12月3日
The 3rd of December
十年前的今天
exactly 1 0 years ago.
他的行李呢?
His luggage?
在旅馆里
Remained at the hotel.
从那些东西里找不到什么线索--
Oh there was nothing in it to suggest a clue --
只有一些衣服 一些书
some clothes, some books,
还有很多Andaman岛上
and a considerable number of curiosities
带回来的古玩
from the Andaman Islands.
我父亲是那儿的一个军官
My father had been one of the officers
负责看守犯人
in charge of the convict-guard there.
华生 这地方有点乱
Watson this place is a mess.
他在伦敦有朋友吗?
Had he any friends in town?
我只知道一个人
Only one that we know of
叫Sholto少校 和他在一个团里
Major Sholto, of his old regiment,
驻孟买陆军第三十四团
the 34th Bombay Infantry.
当然我联系过他
We communicated with the Major, of course,
但是他似乎不知道
but he did not seem to know
他的好兄弟来到英国
that his brother officer was in England.
真是个奇怪的案子
It's a singular case.
我还没和你说到
I have not yet communicated to you
最奇怪的部分呢
the most singular part.
4年后
4 years later
泰晤士报上有一则广告
an advertisement had appeared in the Times
征询我的地址
asking for the address of Miss Mary Morstan,
声称要是回复他
and stating that it would be to her advantage
就会会有好处
to come forward.
广告没有署名
There was no name appended.
那时侯
I had at the time
我刚刚进入Cecil Forrester夫人家
just entered the family of Mrs. Cecil Forrester
做家庭教师
in the capacity of governess
按照她的建议 我把地址登在了
and on her advice I published my address
报纸的广告专栏上
in the advertisement column.
就在同一天有个邮递员送给我
That same day there appeared through the post
一个小纸盒
a small cardboard box addressed to me,
盒里装的是
which I found to contain
一个很大的上等珍珠
a very large and lustrous pearl.
盒里没有一个字
No word of writing was enclosed.
从那以后 每年的这天
And since then every year upon the same date
都会有同样的盒子给我
there has always appeared a similar box,
里面是同样的珍珠
containing a similar pearl,
没有任何寄珠人的线索
with no clue as to the sender.
行家鉴定了之后
They have been pronounced by an expert
说是很稀有的种类
to be of a rare variety
很值钱
and of considerable value.
你们请看
You can see for yourself
的确很上等
that they are very handsome.
你的案子很有趣
Your case is most interesting.
还有别的情况吗?
Something else has occurred to you?
是的 就在今天
Yes, and no later than today.
这就是我来找你的原因
That is why I have come to you.
今早我收到一封信
This letter arrived through the post this morning,
您还是自己读读吧
which you will perhaps read for yourself.
请把信封也给我
Envelope please.
伦敦的邮戳 9月7日
London postmark, October 7th.
角上有个男人的大拇指印
Man's thumb mark on corner
可能是邮递员留下的
probably the postman.
最好的纸
Best quality paper.
六便士一包
Sixpence a packet.
这人对信纸和信封都很讲究
Particular man in his stationery.
华生
Watson.
"今晚7时请到
Be at the third pillar from the left
"Lyceum剧场外
outside the Lyceum Theatre
"左数第三根柱子
tonight at seven o'clock.
"如您怀疑 可偕友二人同来
If you are distrustful bring 2 friends.
"您是受了委屈的女子 定将得到公道
You are a wronged woman and shall have justice.
"别带警察来
Do not bring the police.
"要不然 一切都是徒劳
If you do, all will be in vain.
"您不知名的朋友"
Your unknown friend.
嗯 有点小问题
Well, really,
你打算怎么办 Morstan小姐?
this is a very pretty little problem.
这正是我要问你的
What do you intend to do, Miss Morstan?
我和你一起去
Well that is exactly what I want to ask you.
Well then you and I shall go together.
华生医生也很重要
Dr. Watson is the very man.
上面说两位朋友
Your correspondent says 2 friends.
但是他会去吗?
But would he come?
我很荣幸
I shall be proud and happy
为你效力
if I can be of any service.
你们俩太好了
You are both very kind.
我生活很孤独
I have led a retired life
没有朋友可以相托
and have no friends whom I could appeal to.
我6点来 行吗
If I am here at 6 it will do, I suppose?
最晚6点 再见 Morstan小姐
Yes but you must not be later.
再见 福尔摩斯先生
Goodbye Miss Morstan.
再会
Goodbye Mr. Holmes.
Au revoir.
买束花吧
Buy a flower dearie.
Buy a flower.
买束花吧
Aw come on dearie.
抱歉
Excuse me.
多有魅力的女人啊!
What a very attractive woman
最重要的事就是
It is of the first importance
不要让一个人的特质
not to allow your judgment to be biased
影响了你的判断力
by personal qualities.
一个委托人在我看来 仅仅是一个单元
A client to me is a mere unit,
问题中的一个元素
a factor in of the problem.
福尔摩斯 你真是个机器人
Holmes, you are a automaton
一台计算器
and a calculating machine.
有时你一点人情味儿都没有
There's something positively inhuman in you at times.
我告诉你
I assure you
我生平所见最迷人的女人
the most winning woman I ever knew
毒死了三个孩子
was hanged for poisoning 3 little children
只为了骗取保险金
for their insurance money,
我还认识一个模样无比讨厌的男人
and the most repellent man of my acquaintance
却是个慈善家 捐赠大约25英镑
is a philanthropist who has spent nearly
给伦敦的贫民
a quarter of a million upon the London poor.
但是 在这件案子里...
However, in this case,
我从不例外
I never make exceptions.
定律没有例外
An exception disproves the rule.
我要出去了 一小时后见
I'm going out. I'll see you in an hour.
他在城里有朋友吗
Had he any friends in town?
只有一个
Only one that we know of,
叫Sholto少校 以前和他在一个团里
Major Sholto of his own regiment.
案子没什么神秘的
There is no great mystery in this matter
这些事实看来只有一种解释
the facts appear to admit of only one explanation.
你已经弄清楚了吗?
Oh so you've solved it already?
我发现在过期的泰晤士报上说
I have found,
住在上诺伍德的Sholto少校
on consulting the back files of the Times,
以前驻孟买陆军第三十四兵团
that Major Sholto, of Upper Norwood,
late of the 34th Bombay Infantry,
于6年前死亡
died just 6 years ago.
Hudson太太 您在这儿 还真是碍手碍脚
Mrs. Hudson you're dreadfully under foot.
也许我脑筋迟钝 福尔摩斯
I may be very obtuse, Holmes,
可我看不出这有什么启示
but I fail to see what this suggests.
真看不出?
Really?
没想到
You surprise me.
我们这么来看吧
Now look at it this way, then.
Morstan上尉失踪了
Captain Morstan disappears.
在伦敦 只有一个人他可能去拜访
The only person in London
那就是Sholto少校
whom he could have visited is Major Sholto.
Sholto少校否认知道 他曾来过伦敦
Major Sholto denies having heard
4年后Sholto死了
that he was even in London.
他死后不到一个星期
4 years later Sholto dies.
Within a week of his death
Morstan上尉的女儿
Captain Morstan's daughter
收到了一份价值连城的礼物
receives a valuable present,
以后每年收到一次
which is repeated from year to year
现在她又收到一封信
and now culminates in a letter,
说她是位受了委屈的女子
which describes her as a wronged woman.
她受过什么委屈呢?
Now what wrong can it possibly refer to
除了她丧父以外?
except this deprivation of her father?
卷尺
Tape measure,
枪
gun.
为什么这些礼物
And why should these presents
是在Sholto死后才送给她?
begin immediately after Sholto's death
除非是Sholto的后人
unless it is that Sholto's heir
知道其中的秘密
knows something of the mystery
想要做些补偿
and desires to make compensation?
准备好了吗 华生?
Are you ready Watson?
就等你了
And waiting.
你还有别的想法
Have you any alternative theory
可以解释这些事实?
that will meet the facts?
但 这真是个奇怪的补偿!
But what a strange compensation!
太奇怪了!
And how strangely made!
几点了?
What time is it?
6点15
It's a quarter past the hour.
晚上好 Ellis
Evening Ellis.
晚上好 先生
Evening sir.
为什么那个人
Why should somebody
现在才给她写信
write her a letter now,
而不是6年前呢?
rather than 6 years ago?
信上又说要还她公道
Again, the letter speaks of giving her justice.
她可以得到什么公道呢?
What justice can she have?
要说是她父亲还活着
It is too much to suppose
那未免太乐观
that her father is still alive
可是你又不知道
and there's no other injustice
她还受过什么别的委屈
in her case that you know of.
确实有些费解之处
There are difficulties
但事情总是如此
but there are always difficulties.
晚上好 福尔摩斯先生
Good evening Mr Holmes.
-我想我没... -晚上好
I do hope I'm not...
Good evening.
顺便说一声
By the way,
在爸爸的书桌里找到张奇怪的纸
a curious paper was found in Papa's desk,
没人能看懂
which nobody could understand.
我想这未必和案子有关
I don't suppose it is of the slightest importance,
但我想你可能愿意看一看
but I thought you might like to see it,
所以我带来了
so I brought it with me.
这纸像是印度产的
The paper appears to be of Indian manufacture.
以前被钉在了板子上
At some point it's been pinned to a board.
上面的图表像是
The diagram upon it appears to be the plan
大建筑物草图的一部分
of part of a large building
里面有许多房间 走廊和过道
with numerous halls, corridors, and passages.
上面用红笔画了个十字
There's a cross in red ink,
在一边写着"从左边3.37"
and on the side is written '3.37 from left.'
这有一个奇怪的象形文字
There is a curious hieroglyphic,
四个签名
The sign of four
Kartar Singh Indigo Singh
Kartar Singh, Indigo Singh,
Jagodish Singh Jonathan Small
Jagodish Singh, Jonathan Small.
这纸像是在钱夹里小心收藏过
It appears it has been kept carefully in a pocketbook,
因为纸两边都很干净
for the one side is as clean as the other.
就是在他的钱夹里发现的
It was in his pocketbook that we found it.
好好保管 Morstan小姐
Preserve it carefully, Miss Morstan.
现在我觉得这个案子
I begin to suspect that this case may be
似乎比最初想像的
much deeper and more subtle
更深奥更复杂
than I ever first supposed.
你们就是Morstan小姐 和她的同伴吗
Hey, are you the parties
我就是Morstan小姐
who come with Miss Morstan?
这两位是我的朋友
I'm Miss Morstan,
and these 2 gentlemen are my companions.
您得向我保证
I must ask you to give me your word
您的两位同伴中
that neither of your companions
没有警官
is a police officer.
我保证
I give you my word.
我的主人正在等候
Sahib awaits you.
让他们进来 我的男仆
Show them in, Khitmutgar.
直接把他们带到我这儿来
Show them straight in to me.
愿意为您效劳 Morstan小姐
Your servant, Miss Morstan.
愿意为两位效劳 先生们
Your servant, gentlemen.
进来 进来 进来
Come in.
进我这间小屋子来
Come in to my little sanctum.
我想你们不会介意
I trust you have no objection
烟草味儿吧?
to tobacco smoke?
有香油味儿的
The balsamic odor
东方烟草
of Eastern tobacco?
我有点紧张
I am a little nervous
我发现我的水烟袋是无上的...
and I find my hookah to be an invaluable...
...镇静剂
sedative.
打扰了 Sholto先生
You will excuse me Mr. Sholto
您让我来这里
but I am here at your request
是想告诉我
to learn something,
什么事情呢?
which you desire to tell me?
天有些晚了
It is getting very late and I should wish
我希望谈话越简短越好
the interview to be as short as possible.
嗯 要花些时间
Well it must take some time.
因为我们要去诺伍德
For we have to go to Norwood
见我哥哥Bartholomew
to see brother Bartholomew.
我们都要去
We must all see
也许我们可以说服
if we can get the better
of brother Bartholomew.
我哥哥Bartholomew
他对我发了火
He is angry with me for
因为我采取了我以为正确的行动
taking the course that has seemed right to me.
你们不知道
You cannot imagine
当他生气的时候
what a terrible fellow he is
会是个多么难缠的人
when he is angry.
要是我们去诺伍德
If we are to go to Norwood,
最好还是现在就动身
it would perhaps be as well
不
if we were start at once.
那不合适
No.
No that would hardly do.
我不知道怎么和他说
I don't know what he would say
要是我们这么唐突去见他
if we came upon him in that sudden way.
我必须让你们做好准备
No I must prepare you
把咱们彼此的处境
by showing you where we all stand
先谈一谈
to each other.
首先我要把我知道的一些事实
I must lay the facts before you,
告诉各位
as I know them myself.
我父亲 就是已故的John Sholto少校
My father, the late Major John Sholto,
大约11年前来到上诺伍德
came to live at Pondicherry Lodge
定居于Pondicherry别墅
in Upper Norwood
some 1 1 years ago.
他在印度发了财
And he had prospered in India
带回来了
and brought back with him
一大笔钱
a considerable sum of money,
还有一批珍贵的古董
a collection of valuable curiosities,
和几个印度的仆人
and a staff of native servants.
因为这些
With these advantages
他生活得很富裕
he lived in great luxury.
那时我哥哥和我正在上大学
My brother and I were at university at the time.
然而 我们确实清楚
We did know, however,
有些秘密
that some mystery,
某种存在的危险
some positive danger,
藏在我父亲的心里
overhung our father.
他非常害怕
He was very fearful
独自一人外出
of going out alone,
他雇了2个职业拳击手
and he employed 2 prizefighters
保护他
to guard him.
Williams 今晚送你们来的那个人
Williams, who drove you here tonight,
就是其中之一
was one of them.
出于某种原因
For some reason,
他从不告诉我们
he never told anyone,
我父亲对装有木腿的人格外提防
my father had a marked aversion
to men with wooden legs.
有一次他竟然开枪打伤了
On one occasion
he actually fired his revolver
一个只有一条腿的人
at a one-legged man.
那人只不过是个平常的商贩
A harmless tradesman as it turned out.
我记得当时我们 赔了很大一笔钱才了事
I remember we have to pay
a considerable sum to hush it up.
然后 突然
Then suddenly
我父亲收到了一封信
my father received a letter
那封信对他是很大的打击
It was a great shock to him.
出去
Out.
从房间出去!
Out of the room!
信上说了什么
What was in the letter
我们永远不知道
we could never discover?
我父亲多年身患
For years my father had suffered
脾脏肿大的毛病
with an enlarged spleen
从那时起
and from that moment on
他的病情变得更糟
he became rapidly worse.
一天晚上医生通知我们说 没希望了
But one night the doctor informed us there was no hope
要我们听他的最后的遗嘱
and that he wished to make a last communication to us.
我亲爱的家人
My dear family,
我在印度的时候
when we were in India
我的朋友 Morstan和我
my friend, Morstan and I,
得到了一大笔的
came into possession
宝物
of a considerable treasure.
我把它们带回了这里
I brought it home with me to this house,
至今还在这
where it's still alive.
那天 Morstan先生
On the day, Mr. Morstan,
从印度回来
had arrived home from the East.
他直接找到这里
He came straight to this house
指责我独吞了财宝
to claim his share.
我们发过誓 Sholto
We gave our word Sholto.
一个诺言
A promise.
我们发过毒誓
We gave our word and our oath.
另一时间
another time,
另一种生活 另一个世界
another life, another world,
一个庄严的诺言
a solemn promise.
你背叛了我 Morstan
You tried to betray me Morstan.
要是你敢背叛我...
If you dare to cross me...
上帝
My God.
他死了 Altada
The man is dead Altada.
不用害怕 先生
You have nothing to fear Sir.
下面的我来安排
I will arrange everything.
一会他就弄完了 Morstan小姐
And soon it was done Miss Morstan,
当然是极其秘密的
in secrecy of course
但是不失尊重
but with respect.
这确实很可耻 Sholto先生
This is disgraceful Mister Sholto.
你父亲的行为是不可原谅的
Your father's behavior was quite unforgivable.
拜托 医生
Please Doctor.
我打心底知道
I knew in my heart
他已死了
that he was dead.
但我父亲并不孤单
My father was not alone then.
我很高兴他没受罪
And I'm glad he didn't suffer.
你很勇敢 Morstan小姐
You're very brave Miss Morstan.
现在我所关心的是那场争吵
What concerns me now
我不能想象
is the wishing for this quarrel.
我父亲是怎么卷进这个财宝的
I cannot imagine how my father
came to be involved with that treasure.
恐怕事情还不清楚 Morstan小姐
I'm afraid that is not clear Miss Morstan
我只能告诉你
I can only tell you
我父亲对我们说的
my father's instructions concerning it.
贪...婪
The greed.
可憎的贪婪一生折磨着我
accursed greed that has been
my besetting thing throughout my life
我抢走了她的财产
has robbed her of the treasure.
至少有一半是她的
Half of which, at least,
应该还给她
should be hers.
你们看这串项链
You see that chaplet there.
我想把它送给她
I had the design of sending it to her
但是又舍不得
but could not bear to part with it.
你们
You
我的儿子们
my sons
一定要让Morstan小姐
must see that Miss Morstan
得到属于她的一份
gets her share of the treasure.
把他赶走
Get him away.
看在上帝的份上 把他赶走
For Christ's sake get him away.
我们冲到窗前 跑到花园中
We ran to the window and out into the garden
但是那个人已经没了
but the intruder was gone.
我父亲死了
My father was dead.
不久我们就得到了更确切的证明
We soon had more striking proof that there were
有秘密组织在盯着我们
secret agencies that work all around us.
第二天有人闯进我父亲的卧室
The next day my father's bedroom was broken into
这个被放在了他的胸前
and this was fixed to his chest.
很关键
Remarkable.
这是印度锡克教数字4的标记
It is the Sikkh symbol for the numeral 4.
这张纸是什么意思
What the paper means
还有我们神秘的来访者是谁
and who our secret visitor or visitors were
我们都不知道
we never found out.
我哥哥和我都很兴奋
And my brother and I were much excited
你们能想象出来
as you could imagine
都是由于我父亲说的财宝
of the treasure that my father had spoken
但是 我们竭尽所能都没有找到
but try as we might we couldn't find it.
我们有些发狂 只要想到收藏宝藏的地方
It was maddened to think that the hiding place
就在他临终的嘴边
was on his very lips when he died.
从这个项链上 我们就可以
We could judge the splendor of the riches
看出这批财宝的贵重
by the chaplet, which he had taken out.
这几颗珍珠都很值钱
The pearls were evidently of great value,
我哥哥不愿意把它们给她
and my brother was averse to part with them,
在对待朋友上
for, between friends,
他也有点我父亲的缺点
he was a little inclined to my father's fault.
我所能做的只是规劝他
And it was all I could do was to persuade him
允许我每隔一段时间给Morstan小姐
to allow me to send Miss Morstan
一颗拆下来的珍珠
a detached pearl at regular intervals
这样她就不会生活拮据了
so that she would not feel destitute.
真是好心眼
It was a kindly thought.
你真是太好心了
No it was very good of you.
我们只是你的托管人
We were your trustees
这是我的看法
that was the way I looked at it,
虽然我哥哥和我看法不同
although my brother
我们自己有很多钱
did not altogether see it in that light.
We had plenty of money ourselves.
用卑劣的手段
It would have been in such bad taste
对待一位年轻的女士
to have treated a young lady
实在是情理难容
in so scurvy a fashion.
就在昨天
Yesterday an event
发生了一件极其重要的事
of extreme importance occurred.
我们找到财宝了
We, found of the treasure.
因此 我立即联系了Morstan小姐
Hence my instant communication to you Miss Morstan.
我们现在要做的就是去诺伍德
Now all we have to do is to drive to Norwood
向他索要我们应得的那份
and claim our share.
在他眼中 我们也许是
We shall be expected,
不受欢迎的客人
if not entirely welcome, visitors.
你从头到尾做得都很好 Sholto先生
You have done well from first to last Mr. Sholto.
我身体很弱
My health is somewhat fragile.
只能算个病人
I am compelled to be a valetudinarian.
请
Please?
花园的每个角落我们都挖过
We dug up every inch of the garden
没有任何发现
without discovering anything.
我哥哥Bartholomew很聪明
Brother Bartholomew is such a clever fellow.
你们知道他是怎样
Do you know how he found out
发现宝藏的吗
where the treasure was?
说
Tell me.
他测量了每个角落
He made measurements everywhere,
从上面
all along the top,
侧面 里面
along the side, inside and he found out
最后在离房顶4英尺的地方
he was 4 foot out at the top.
我们发现了父亲建的一个小顶楼
We found our father made a false room
他在板条灰泥天花板上打了个洞
So he smashed through the lath and the plaster
宝箱就在...
and there was the treasure chest
椽木上
lying across the rafters.
他估算了一下
He has computed the value of the treasure
差不多超过...
50万英镑
to be more than one half million sterling.
[scream]
是Bernstone夫人
It's Mrs. Bernstone.
Bernstone夫人是这房子里唯一的女人
Mrs. Bernstone is the only lady in the house
在这等着
wait here.
Thaddeus先生 真高兴您来了
Oh, Mr. Thaddeus I'm so glad you've come!
真高兴您来了 先生
I'm so glad you've come, sir!
真是个奇怪的地方!
What a strange place!
好像全英国的鼹鼠都跑到这来了
It looks as if all the moles in England
have been let loose in it.
Bartholomew好像出事了
There's something amiss with Bartholomew
进屋去!
Into the house!
上帝保佑 看您这张甜美安静的脸多好
bless your sweet, calm face.
我这一天可真是受够了
Oh, but I have been sorely tried this day.
怎么了 Bernstone夫人?
How Mrs. Bernstone?
Bartholomew先生把自己关在屋里
Mr. Bartholomew shut himself in his room
没和我说一句话
and I can't get a word out of him.
没有睡觉
His bed hasn't been slept in
也没下楼吃过东西
and he hasn't been down for any food.
他工作的时候我不敢打扰他
I dare not disturb him at his work.
你知道他工作时候的样子
You know what he's like when it's his work.
照顾好她 Morstan小姐
Look after her Miss Morstan.
来 冷静一下
There, there do try to calm down.
瞧 一切都会好的
Look I'm sure everything will be all right.
希望你是对的 小姐
I do hope your right Miss.
坐这里
Sit down over there.
过来
Come.
哪个门?
Which is the door?
里面情况很糟糕 华生
There's something devilish in this, Watson.
又是四签名
The sign of the four again.
这一切是怎么回事?
What in God's name does it all mean?
谋杀
It means murder.
昨晚我们把财宝搬下来 放在那里
We brought the treasure down there last night.
现在不见了
Now its gone.
那是几点的事
What time is that?
不...不知道
I don't know.
我想是6点或是7点
I think six, or seven.
我走后听见他锁门了
I heard him lock the door after I left.
我一定是最后见到他活着的人
I must have been the last person to see him alive.
现在他死了
And now he's dead
你想是我干的?
you think I did it?
我没有 为什么我要...
I didn't, why should I,
我不会让你...
I wouldn't have wanted you...
我不会请你来...
I wouldn't have asked you to...
我要疯了
冷静 冷静 冷静  Sholto先生
I'll go mad.
我建议你报警
Gentle, gently, gentle Mr. Sholto.
把你知道的一切告诉他们
I suggest that you go down to the police station
我们等你回来
and tell them everything that you know.
We shall wait here until you return.
福尔摩斯 看这个
Holmes look at this.
小心
Careful!
上面有毒
Forgive me, its poisoned.
华生 我们还有些时间
Well Watson we have a little time
弄清楚整个过程
let's make the most of it.
这件事真是扑朔迷离
Awe this is an Insoluble mystery to me.
不止没搞明白 反而越来越糊涂了
It grows darker instead of clearer.
不 不 不 马上就会水落石出
No, no, no, no it clears every instant.
我只要再弄清几个环节
I only require a few missing links
就可以把整个案子串联起来
to have an entirely connected case.
现在案子看上去很简单了
Simple as the case seems now
还有几件事不明白
there may be something deeper underlying it.
这些人怎么进来的
How did these people come
怎么出去的
and how did they go?
这些人?
People?
要从这种地方搬走财宝箱
Well it takes more than one, perhaps more than 2
需要不止一个人 或许两人以上
to remove a heavy treasure chest
门从昨晚就没开过
from a place like this.
The door hasn't been opened since last night.
那这些窗户呢?
So how about these windows?
插销在里面
Snibbed on the inside.
没有合叶
No hinges.
屋顶离的很远
Roof quite out of reach.
附近没有排水管
No drainpipe near.
有人可能从这进来 看 华生
Yet someone has entered this way look.
窗台上有足迹
Watson.
See that a scuff on the sill.
看这个 华生
Look at this Watson
这儿和这儿
and this and this.
这真是个非常好的证据
This is a very pretty demonstration.
但那不是脚印
But that's not a footmark.
这东西对我们更有价值
Something much more valuable to us.
这个靴子的痕迹
This is mark of a boot and this
这是木腿的痕迹
this the mark of the timber toe.
他是一个有一条木腿的人
It is a wooden-legged man.
而另一个人是
And someone else.
很能干 很灵活的同谋
A very able and efficient ally.
你能从那个墙爬过来吗 华生?
Could you scale that wall, Watson?
肯定不能
Absolutely impossible.
没有帮忙是不能的
I aid it is so
但假定你有一个朋友
but suppose you had a friend
他把这根结实的绳子
who lowered you this good stout rope
牢牢的系在那个环子上
securing it first to this ring.
我想只要你有力气
I think if you were an active man,
你就可以爬过去
you'd be able to swarm up,
即使是装着木腿
wooden leg and all.
你离开的时候 当然
You would depart, of course,
可以用同样的方式
in the same fashion, and then your friend
你的朋友会收起绳子
would pull up the rope,
关上窗子
close the window,
从里面栓牢
snib it on the inside,
把它复原成来时候的样子
and depart in the manner he originally came.
情况比刚才更莫名其妙了
Well the thing grows more unintelligible than ever.
这个神秘的同谋是谁?
How about this mysterious ally?
他是怎样进屋的?
How did he get into the room?
不错 那个同谋
Yes, this ally.
他使案子变得
He lifts this case
异乎寻常
from the regions of the commonplace.
门是关着的 窗户够不到
Well the door is locked; the window inaccessible.
壁炉又太小
The grate's too small.
怎么办到的呢?
How then?
你总是不跟着我的思路
You will not follow my precept.
我和你说过多少次了
How often have I said to you
一旦你排除掉不可能的因素
that once you have eliminated the impossible,
不论剩下什么
whatever remains,
不论多么不可能
however improbable,
那一定是事实
must be the truth?
他肯定是从屋顶下来的
He must of come in through the roof.
好极了 华生 拿着灯
Excellent Watson, hold this lamp.
咱们去查看一下上面的空间
Let us carry our research to the room above
就是放财宝的密室
the secret room in which the treasure was found.
天窗
The skylight.
福尔摩斯 是个小孩干了这么恐怖的事
Holmes a child has done this horrid thing.
我忘记了
My memory failed me,
我本应该料到的
for I should have been able to foretell it.
这里没什么可搜的了
There is nothing we can learn from here.
我们下去吧
Let us go down.
你对那些脚印有什么结论?
What is your theory about those footmarks?
华生 请你自己做点分析
My dear Watson, try a little analysis yourself.
你知道我的方法
You know my methods.
应用他们
Apply them.
我从这些证据上
I cannot conceive of anything
什么也总结不出来
that will cover the facts.
你不久就会清楚了
You will soon.
我们运气好
We're in luck.
我们的小同谋
Our little ally
踩到了木馏油
has trod in the creosote.
[Voices from afar].
看那个
Ahh, look at that.
你们住的小地方还真好
Quite a nice little place you got here.
福尔摩斯!
Holmes!
我猜是那些法律的代表者们
representatives of the law
要不就是我犯了非常大的错误
unless I'm very, very much mistaken.
华生
Now Watson
在他们来之前
before they come
你对这个可怜的家伙有什么看法?
what do you make of this poor fellow?
肌肉像木板一样僵硬
The muscles are stiff as a board.
极其强烈的收缩状态
A state of extreme contraction,
远比一般的死后僵硬要厉害
far exceeding the usual rigor mortis.
很对
Quite so.
再加上脸部的扭曲
Coupled with this distortion of the face,
希波克拉底式的笑容
the Hippocratic smile,
这是被老派作家称为讥笑的笑容
risus sardonicus, as the old writers called it,
你心里有结论了吗?
what would that suggest to your mind?
死于某种植物性生物碱的剧毒
Death from a powerful vegetable alkaloid
某种番木鳖碱
some strychnine-like substance
能造成破伤风
that produces tetanus.
Well,
右转
to the right,
先生们 向右转
come on along gentleman to the right.
上楼梯
Up these stairs.
这根荆棘
This thorn.
英国荆棘
old English thorn.
我想不应该让Morstan小姐
I think it is not right that Miss Morstan
呆在这个遭殃的屋子里了
remain in this stricken house.
你把他送回家去 华生
I suggest you slip away and take her home Watson
然后去Pinchin巷 3号
and then go to 3 Pinchin Lane,
Lambeth区 找Toby来
Lambeth and ask for Toby.
Pinchin巷 3号
3 Pinchin Lane.
我宁愿要Toby的帮忙
I'd rather have Toby's help than that of the
比全伦敦的警察都得力
whole protective force London.
这成什么样子了!
Well here's a pretty business!
屋里挤得像个养兔场!
Place is as full as a rabbit-warren!
我想你一定还记得我吧
I think you better recollect me,
Athelney Jones先生
Mr. Athelney Jones.
我当然记得!
Why, of course I do!
夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生 大理论家
Mr. Sherlock Holmes, the theorist.
我永远忘不掉 那次你给我们做的演讲
I'll never forget that you lectured us all
关于那件主教珍宝案
about the Bishopgate jewel case.
你确实把我们引上正确的思路
True you set us on the right track then
我想你得承认
I think you'll own now
那是因为运气好而不是正确的引导
it is more by good luck than good guidance.
那是一个很简单的推理
It was a piece of very simple reasoning.
算了吧
Oh, come, now, come!
别不好意思承认
Never be ashamed to own up.
可这是怎么一回事?
But what is all this?
太糟糕了
It's a bad business!
太糟糕了!
Bad business!
严酷的事实摆在这
Stern facts here
用不着理论了
no room for theories.
真是太巧了 我路过诺伍德
It's lucky I happened to be up at Norwood
接到报案时 我正在忙另一个案子
on another case when I got the message.
你认为这人是怎么死的?
How do you think this man died?
这个案子似乎不需要我的理论
This is not a case for me to theorize over.
是不需要
No, no, no.
可是 我们不得不承认
Still, we can't deny
你有时真能一言中的
you hit the nail on the head sometimes.
门是锁着的
Door locked, I understand.
财宝丢失了
Jewels worth a fortune missing.
窗户的情况怎么样
How were the windows?
关得很紧 不过窗台上有脚印
Fastened; but there was a footstep on the sill.
窗户关着的
Windows fastened.
脚印便与本案无关 这是常识
Nothing to do with it. It's common sense.
我猜这个人是猝死的
Man could have died in a fit I suppose.
哈!
Ha!
我有一个解释
I have a theory.
有时我也能灵机一动呢
These flashes come to me sometimes.
警长 你先出去
Sergeant, outside if you please.
你也是 Sholto先生
And you too, Mr. Sholto.
你怎么想的 福尔摩斯先生?
What do you think of this, Holmes?
Sholto已经承认了
Sholto has confessed
昨晚他和他哥哥在一起
he was with his brother last night.
他哥哥猝死后
The brother died in a fit.
Sholto带着财宝跑了?
Sholto walks off with the treasure?
真是这样吗
How about that?
这个死人倒还细心
Whereupon a dead man very considerately
命都没了还起来把门锁上
gets up and locks the door from the inside.
哼!
Hum!
这是个破绽
There's a flaw there somewhere.
咱们根据常识来想想
Let us apply common sense to the matter.
他们是兄弟
They were brothers
争吵过
there was a quarrel
哥哥Bartholomew死了
brother Bartholomew dead
珠宝不见了
jewels gone.
而Thaddeus
And master Thaddeus
极为恐惧不安
evidently in a disturbed state of mind.
他外表还行 但不怎么迷人
His appearance well, not attractive.
你看
You see
我正在结网 要网住Thaddeus
I'm weaving a web around Thaddeus.
这张网要套住他了
The net begins to close upon him.
Jones
那个小木刺
that splinter,
我想那有毒
which I firmly believe to be poisoned,
那张纸和那根样子奇怪的木棍
that card and that curiously shaped instrument
放在桌子上
were lying there on the table.
从各方面来看
Confirms my theory
都能证实我的结论
in every respect.
这个屋里到处是印度的古玩
The house is full of Indian curiosities.
所有证据都指向Thaddeus
All point to Thaddeus.
但是...
But
他是怎么逃走的呢?
how did he escape?
屋顶上有个洞...警官!
There is a trapdoor in the roof Sergeant.
让Sholto先生进来?
May I ask Mr. Sholto to step this way?
毕竟事实胜于雄辩
You see facts are better than theories, after all.
我的看法完全得到证实
My view of the case is confirmed.
有一个天窗
There is a trapdoor
连接着屋顶
communicating with the roof,
还是半开的
and it is partly open.
那是我打开的
It is I who opened it.
Thaddeus Sholto先生 我有责任告诉你
Mr. Thaddeus Sholto, it is my duty to inform you
你所说的都会被记下
that anything you say will be taken down
可能会对你不利
and maybe used in evidence against you.
为了你死去的哥哥
I arrest you in the Queen's name
我代表政府逮捕你
as being concerned in the death of your brother.
我没有 我说过了吧
I didn't I tell you
别着急 Sholto
Don't trouble yourself, Mr. Sholto.
我能帮你洗刷一切罪名
I think that I can engage
不要随便答应 大理论家
to clear you of this charge.
Don't promise too much, Mr. Theorist.
事实恐怕没你想的那么简单
You may find it a harder matter than you think.
我不但要为他澄清
Not only will I clear Mr. Sholto,
还要给你一些信息
but I will give you a description
昨晚有两个人来这个屋里
of the 2 men who were in this room last night.
其中一个文化程度很低
One was a poorly educated man,
强壮
strong,
动作灵活
active,
没有右腿
with his right leg off,
装了一条木腿
wearing a stump worn away on the inside.
左脚的靴子下面 有一块粗糙的方形前掌
His left boot has a coarse, square-toed sole
后跟上钉着铁掌
it has an iron band around the heel.
是个中年人 晒得很黑
He's much sunburned, middle-aged
这从他手掌上剥落的皮就能看出来
and has a certain amount of skin missing
from the palm of one hand.
那另一个呢?
And the other one?
另一个更加扑朔迷离
He's rather a curious person.
我希望不久就能够
I hope before long to be able to
把他们介绍给你
introduce you to the pair of them.
华生 去Pinchin巷3号
Watson, go to 3 Pinchin Lane, London
把Toby带来
and ask for Toby.
我宁愿要Toby的帮忙
I'd rather have Toby's help
比全伦敦的警察都得力
than that of the whole detective force of London.
Toby先生?
Mr. Toby?
-Toby先生? -滚开
你这醉鬼流浪汉
Get out of it.
You drunken hooligan.
再敲 我就放狗咬你
Go on get out of it or I'll turn my dogs on you.
43条狗
All 43 of them.
我是来找Toby先生的
I'm looking for Mr. Toby.
这袋子里有毒蛇
I have a viper in this bag,
要是你不滚远点
and I'll tip it out over your 'ead
我会把它扔你头上
if you don't hoof it!
我很着急
It's urgent that I find him.
我不想和你多说
I won't be argued with!
-1  2  3 要扔了... -我从福尔摩斯先生那里来
1 , 2, 3 and down comes the viper.
是夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生派来的
I've come from Mr. Holmes.
I've come from Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
夏洛克 福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Sherlock Holmes
谁会想到呢?
well who'd of thought it?
欢迎你
Awe here you are.
夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生 怎么不早说 进来!
Mr. Sherlock Holmes why didn't you say so,
come in.
[inaudible].
它很调皮
Oh yes he does now Naughty.
别咬他
Oh please don't you bite the gentleman
他是夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生的朋友
cause this gentleman is a friend
夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生的朋友
of Mr. Sherlock Holmes
就是我的朋友
and any friend of Mr. Sherlock Holmes
别介意
is a friend of mine.
他只是向你友好地打招呼
Don't mind him.
He'll just give you a nice friendly squeeze.
我把它放在屋里
I've give him the run of the room
是让他吃甲虫的
because he keeps down the beetles something beautiful.
你说夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生要什么
Now what did you say
Toby
Mr. Sherlock Holmes wanted?
Toby?
Toby.
对 Toby
Toby?
Toby在左边的第7个笼子里
Yes Toby.
Awe well Toby's No. 7
你把这个给他
there along on the left.
它就会和你走了
Here you give him these
就像只绵羊
and Toby will go along with you
as quiet as a lamb.
Toby 起来
Hey Toby wake up come on.
有工作了
There's work for you to do.
有人来看你了
A gentleman's come here to see you.
Toby 来
Toby come on.
来 来 Toby
Come on love.
来 Toby
Come on Toby.
华生!
Watson?
没事了 警长 是福尔摩斯先生
It's all right officer it's Mr. Holmes.
停到边上
Coach around.
走 Toby
Come on Toby.
很好 你把Toby带来了
Well done you've got Toby.
从伦敦回来了
Here comes London.
我马上下去
I'm coming down.
福尔摩斯!
Holmes!
Ah,
看这个 华生
look at these Watson.
我在排水沟里发现了这些
I found them in the gutter.
谢谢你 Bernstone夫人
Oh thank you Mrs. Bernstone.
你闻到木榴油的味儿了吗?
Do you smell the creosote?
Athelney Jones不仅逮捕了Thaddeus
Athelney Jones arrested not only Thaddeus
也逮捕了守门人
but also the gatekeeper,
管家
the gamekeeper,
还有两个印度佣人
2 Indian servants.
我很幸运逃过一劫
I was lucky to escape myself.
华生 你能长途跋涉吗?
Watson are you on for a bit of a trudge?
当然
Of course.
你和Toby比一比 顺着他们来的路
You and Toby game as they come
它嗅觉很好使
when it's a good holding scent.
找到他们
Now find him.
去 Toby
Go Toby.
走吧 Toby 快走
Seek Toby seek.
稳住 华生 稳住
Steady Watson steady.
幸好昨晚雨停了
Lucky the rain has stopped.
虽然隔了挺久
The scent will lie on the road
但气味儿还留在路上
in spite of their start.
早上的空气真新鲜
Ah, how sweet the morning air is.
带手枪了吗 华生?
Have you brought your pistol Watson?
没有 我带着手杖
No I have my stick.
要是遇上他们
In the event were led to the men
带假腿的就留给你了
the peg leg I'll leave to you.
那个同伙我来应付
Leave the ally to me come.
这狗是怎么了?
What the deuce is the matter with the dog?
他们坐船走了
They took a boat
至少没有坐马车或是氢气球
except they didn't take a cab or a balloon.
他们一定是在码头会面
They must have been met at the waters edge.
Toby!
毫无差错的Toby也出了错
He's lost his character to infallibility.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
这不怪Toby
Toby's not to blame.
这些桶里装满了木榴油
Those barrels are filled with creosote.
气味儿把它引到这儿来了
The scent was divided.
这和打猎一样 华生
So like good huntsmen Watson.
我们得带着狗再走一遍
We must cast the dog again
找到正确的路
and find the true one.
Toby
我们今天不走运
We're out of luck.
他们从这里坐的船
They've taken the boat from here.
这些人比我想的聪明
These people are cleverer than I thought.
华生 这些人事先有所准备
Now Watson these people show
preconcerted management here.
Mordecai Smith (小船出租 可按时或按日计费)
Mordecai Smith.
回来 洗洗脸
You come back here and get your face washed.
Jack?
你这小鬼
Oh you youngin'.
你爸爸回来以后
I'll get your Dad to give you a good spankin'
又要打你屁股了
when he gets back.
真是个红脸的小淘气!
My what a rosy-cheeked young rascal!
你想要什么东西吗 Jack?
Is there anything you'd like Jack?
我想要一个先令
I'd like a shillin'.
他真是个好孩子 Smith太太
A fine young lad you got there, Mrs. Smith.
上帝保佑你 他一直是这样
Lor' bless you, sir, he is that, and forward.
我简直管不了他
He gets a'most too much for me to manage,
尤其是他爹不在的时候
'specially when my man is away days at a time.
太不巧了
Awe it's a pity about that.
我还想租只船呢
I was hoping to hire a boat from him,
一只汽艇
a steam launch.
哎呀 先生 他就是坐着那只汽艇走的
Why, bless you, sir,
我一点都不喜欢雇他的那人
it is in the steam launch that he has gone.
Aye' didn't like the bloke who did the hire
很粗鲁 装着条假腿
not at all, very rough, with a wooden leg,
半夜来敲我们的窗户
come tappin' at our window
然后没和我交代一句就走了
in the middle of the night
and away they went without a word to me.
那个装着木腿的是一个人吗?
Now this man with the wooden leg, was he alone?
也许他带着一只动物
Think he might have had an animal with him.
厄...一只狗?
A dog?
不像是狗 先生
Didn't look like no dog to me sir.
更像是在动物园能找到的动物
More like something that you find at the zoo.
和我说说汽艇的事
So tell me about the launch.
绿底上有黄线的旧船
It's the old green bird with the yellow line.
不 不
Oh no, no, sir.
"曙光"号新刷的油漆
The Aurora has just been fresh painted
黑底上有两条红线
black with a gold trim.
啊 没错 白色的烟囱
Awe yes, with a white funnel.
不  黑色的烟囱
No sir black funnel.
当然
Awe yes of course.
谢了  Smith夫人
Well thank you Mrs. Smith.
再见  Jack
Goodbye Jack.
再见
Bye.
跟这种人说话关键的就是
The main thing with people of that sort
不要让他们知道 他们的话与你有关
is never to let them think that information
否则的话 他们马上就会三缄其口
is of the slightest importance to you.
If you do they will instantly
shut up like an oyster.
我们的线索看上去清楚了
你会怎么办呢
Well our course seems pretty clear now.
追踪"曙光"号
What would you do, then?
查找这里和Greenwich之间的 每一个码头和卸货地点要花好几天时间
Get on the track of the Aurora.
It would take days if not months
to search every wharf and landing place
你打算怎么办?
on the harbor between here and Greenwich.
既然嫌疑人以为 我们找不到他们
What do you propose?
As our query has no reason to fear that he's being hunted
我想先去洗个澡
I propose first of all a bath.
刮刮脸
And shave.
大吃一顿 再睡上一觉
And then a good meal and then some hours of sleep.
同时
At the same time
动员贝克街上的侦探小分队
mobilizing the Baker Street division
of the detective police force.
换句话说 动用非常手段
In other words the irregulars.
这个精力充沛的Jones和这个平庸的记者
Awe the energetic Jones the ubiquitous reporter
把这个案子给了结了
fixed up the case between them.
华生 看这个
Watson look at this.
这里
Here.
"训练有素 经验丰富的Jones
Mr. Jones' trained and experienced faculties
"立即着手调查案犯
were at once directed towards the detection of the criminals.
"他知识丰富
His well-known technical knowledge
"观察缜密细致..."
and powers of minute observation...
还有更好的呢
well it gets better still
"警署方面及时负责的处理
the prompt and energetic action
"展现了把警备分散各地的好处"
of the officers of the law
shows the great advantage for the
single vigorous and masterful mind.
太伟大了?
Isn't it gorgeous?
我们也险些被逮捕
We had a close shave of being arrested ourselves.
要是他再来个灵机一动
I wouldn't answer for our safety now
我们也可能被认作凶手
if he has another of his attacks of energy.
福尔摩斯先生没说起过此事
Mr Holmes said nothing of this.
你们不能进去
You can't possibly go in there.
抱歉 福尔摩斯先生
I'm sorry Mr. Holmes
没事了 Hudson夫人
It's all right Mrs. Hudson,
他们是我的客人
they are my guests.
听着 帽子摘了
Look, hats off.
我收到您的消息了
I've got your message.
就带他们来了
I brought 'em on sharp.
车费三先令六便士
3 bob and a tenner for the tickets.
Wiggins 以后有事
Now Wiggins, in future
他们就向你汇报 你再告诉我
they can report to you and you to me.
我这屋子容不下这么多人
I cannot have the house invaded in this way.
别动
Oye stop that.
抱歉
Sorry.
我要你们找一艘叫"曙光"号的汽艇
Now I want you to find the steamboat Aurora.
"曙光"号
Aurora.
是Mordecai Smith家的
Owner Mordecai Smith,
黑底有金边
black with gold trim.
从Richmond到Gravesend
Richmond to Gravesend
在河的两岸查找
both sides of the river.
好的 先生
Fine sir.
报酬是多少?
How much?
老规矩
Old scale of pay
找到船的孩子多给一个几尼
a guinea to the boy who finds the boat.
这是预付给你们一天的工钱
Here is a day in advance.
只要这船还停在水上
If the launch is above water
这些非正规军就能找到她
the irregulars will find her.
他们无处不到 一切都逃过他们的眼睛
They can go everywhere, see everything.
咱们这个问题看来不难解决
If our man had an easy task
一只腿的人并不多见
just as ours ought to be.
另一个人也很特殊
One-legged men are not so common
and this other man must be unique.
安达曼群岛的土著居民
The aborigines of the Andaman Islands
或许可以称得上是
may perhaps claim the distinction
世界最矮小的种族了
of being the smallest race upon this earth.
他们生性凶猛 怪癖 难以交往
They are a fierce, morose,
但如果得到他们的信任
and intractable people,
though capable of forming
他们会成为至死不渝的朋友
the most devoted friendships
when their confidence has once been gained.
对于船只的遇难水手来说 他们永远是个祸害
They have always been a terror to shipwrecked crews,
往往被他们用绑着石头的木棒击碎脑袋
braining the survivors with their stone-headed clubs
或是用...
or shooting them with
用毒箭刺死
with poisoned arrows.
通常屠杀之后
These massacres are usually concluded
将人肉作为盛宴
by a cannibal feast.
这真是一群"和善"的人啊
Nice, amiable people.
什么时候吃晚饭 福尔摩斯先生?
And what time would you like for dinner Mr. Holmes?
后天8点半
Half past eight the day after tomorrow.
你会撑不住的
You'll wear yourself out old man.
我听见你整晚上都踱来踱去的
I heard you marching about all night.
你真的需要些休息了
You really must get some rest.
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
这个恶魔似的问题一直困扰着我
This infernal problem is consuming me.
没有消息?
No news?
没有 什么都没有
None.
河的两岸都搜过了
None whatsoever.
Smith夫人也没有他丈夫的消息
The whole river has been searched from both sides.
其他的问题都解决了
Mrs. Smith has not heard from her husband,
it's too much.
To be balked by some petty obstacle
就是这个问题一直阻碍着我们
when all else has been overcome.
看见什么了吗?
See anything?
什么都没有
No nothing.
快下船 否则我就要来赶你了!
Shove off.
Or you'll feel the back of my hand.
"曙光"号
我不想再说一遍了 孩子
I'm not going to tell you again boy.
多漂亮的一搜小船
A nice little craft.
是条不错的船
Aye, she's a good boat this.
我们在这里把它造好的
We built her right in this yard.
在河里行得最快的船
Fastest boat on the river.
为什么停进来?
What she in for?
维修一下方向舵
Repairs to her rudder.
这是惯例
That's the order.
在它身上找不到任何差错
I can't find anything amiss with it.
今晚六点我们的船要出坞了
I want her in the water
by six o'clock tonight.
加满煤 全速前进
Fully coaled and steam up.
Smith先生 准备好了
Right Mr. Smith she'll be ready.
6点要全速前进
Six o'clock sharp, mind,
这两位先生已经等不急了
for 2 gentlemen that'll not be kept waiting.
好的
Right.
就是这个诺伍德案 医生
It's this Norwood case Doctor.
总是有些麻烦困扰着我
I have a great deal to worry and try me.
这桩案子就是之一
And this case is a very dark one too.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很感激福尔摩斯先生的帮助
I shall be most grateful for Mr. Holmes' help.
你的朋友是个好人
Your friend is a wonderful man
谁也比不上他
and not to be beat.
也许你要等很长时间
Well you maybe in for a long wait.
我不这么想
Nope I don't think so.
"马上去贝克街
Go to Baker Street at once.
"要是我没回来 等着我
If I've not returned, wait for me.
"我已找到Sholto案匪徒的踪迹
I am close on the track of the Sholto gang.
"要是想看到本案的结局
Come with us tonight
"今晚和我们同去"
if you want to be in at the kill.
不错 他又找到线索了
Good.
So he's on the scent again?
之前他也查错了方向?
He's been at fault too has he?
我们最好的侦探专家 有时也难免被人甩了
Even the best of us are thrown off sometimes.
-什么事? -夏洛克 福尔摩斯?
Yes?
-怎么了? -你是夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生?
Sherlock Holmes?
What is it?
Are you Mr. Sherlock Holmes?
不 但是我可以代表他
No but I'm acting for him.
我是为这个到这里来
I've come about this right here.
要是你有什么事 你可以和我说
If you have any information
-这个酬金... -是关于汽艇"曙光"号的吗?
you may give to me.
There's a reward.
Is it about the steam launch, Aurora?
我只跟夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生说
I'm telling no one but Mr. Sherlock Holmes.
别走 进来
No, no; come inside.
我是个警官
I'm a police officer.
你看上去就像
You look like one.
我们会补偿你的
No you will be recompensated
作为你时间的损失
for your loss of time.
不会等太久的 坐下
You will not have long to wait.
Sit down.
要雪茄吗 Jones先生?
Cigar Mr. Jones?
谢谢
Oh, thank you for you very much.
我说 医生
As I was saying Doctor,
我认为你的朋友
I consider your friend
夏洛克・福尔摩斯先生 是一个不会被打败的人
Mr. Sherlock Holmes is a man not to be beat.
他本可以成为最有前途的警官
He would have made
这话我可以当着任何人讲
the most promising police officer.
只要稍微循规蹈矩一点
I don't care who knows it.
With a little more discipline
别死抱着理论不放
and a lot less theory.
谢谢
Thank you.
你或许可以给我提供机会
You might offer me one.
你这坏蛋
Oh, you rogue
你可以去做演员了
you would have made an actor
出色的演员
and a rare one.
咳嗽声惟妙惟肖
You had the proper workhouse cough,
两条弱不禁风的腿
and those weak legs of yours
上台表演能挣10英镑了
there worth 1 0 pounds each.
我能胜任警官的职位 您太过奖了
A police officer, I'm flattered.
Jones 我要一只警用汽艇
Jones I shall need a police launch
在威斯敏斯特待命
at the Westminster steps.
最快的那种
The fastest you have.
还有两位健壮的警察  你  我
2 stout men, yourself, myself,
还有华生 都要有武器
Watson all of us armed.
这容易安排
That is easily arranged.
我给当地警局打电话
I will telephone the local station.
到伦敦塔的时候
When we get to the tower
把船停在Jacobson船坞的对面
we'll stop opposite of Jacobson's Yard.
你是怎么找到"曙光"号的?
How did you find the Aurora then?
我有理由相信汽艇就在不远处
Well I have reasons that the launch couldn't be
虽然我们看不见它
far often despite of its invisibility.
所以 先生们 它会在哪里?
So gentlemen, where could it be?
我猜肯定不在水上
Well out of the water I suppose.
在船坞里小做修整
In a repair or boat builders yard.
非常正确
Exactly.
一个孩子正在那里等着
One of my boys is waiting by the yard
他会给我们信号
to give us the signal.
你的计划非常周密 福尔摩斯先生
You planned it all very neatly Mr. Holmes
不过要由我处理这件事
but if the affair were in my hands
我一定派出一对能干的警察
I should have a body of police in the yard
等他们来了把他们都逮捕了
and arrested them when they came down.
那绝不可能
Which would have been never.
那个叫Small的人很精明
This man Small is a pretty shrewd fellow.
如有可疑情况
Anything suspicious
他可能会再躲一个星期
and he would lie snug for another week.
先生?
Sir?
我们已经到了Jacobson船坞的对面
We're opposite Jacobson's Yard now,
要靠近一些吗
shall we move downstream a little.
不用 雾气会掩护我们
No this mist may be of an advantage to us.
我们下去等着
We must lie low and wait.
你的男孩发信号了
Your boy's signaling,
我看得很清楚
I can see it plainly.
那就是"曙光"号
There's the Aurora
像艘鬼船
going like the devil
她太快了
She's very fast.
我猜我们追不上她
I doubt if we shall catch her.
我们必须追上她!
We must catch her!
火夫 赶紧加煤!
Pile it on, stokers!
要是我们追不上她
I'll never forgive myself
我永远不能原谅自己
if she proves to have some use.
再快点 再快点
Faster, faster.
这已经是我们的极限了
This is the fast boat they've got.
快加煤 火夫!
Pile on the coals.
一定要追上
Stoke her.
就算把船烧了
We must have her.
Even if we burn the boat.
灯照别太晃
Keep the light steady.
我几乎看清他的同伙了
I can almost make out his companion.
我们快追上了
We're gaining.
火夫 赶紧加煤!
Pile it on, stoker.
全速前进
Give it all the steam we've got.
我们赶上了一些
I think we gained a little.
我一定以及肯定
I'm sure of it.
Absolutely.
把灯向左边照照
Point the light more to the left.
稳住
Keep it steady.
那艘船怎么了?
What's happening on that boat?
他们自己打起来了
They're fighting among themselves.
Tonga
Tonga,
Tonga.
那个木腿人
The peg leg.
停船!
Stop!
我们是警察!
Police!
快停下!
Cease you.
你们下地狱吧!
You can burn in hell
停下!
Stop!
四签名
The sign of four
华生 看
Watson look.
多可怕的脸
What a face.
等等
Wait
Wait.
等他筋疲力尽了再说
Let him wear himself out.
Jonathan Small
So Jonathan Small.
抱歉 事情变成这样
I am sorry it's come to this.
我也一样
And so am I sir.
但是我发誓 先生们
But I give you my word gentlemen
我没有对小Sholto先生下手
I never laid hands on young Mr. Sholto.
你当然没有
Of course you didn't.
你那个小朋友杀了他
Your little friends dart killed him
就在你还在爬绳子的时候
while he was still climbing the rope.
你说这话就好像你亲眼见过一样
Well you speak as if you were there sir.
要是那是老Sholto少校的话
Well if it had been old Major Sholto
我绝对会毫不手软地掐死他
I would have swung for him with a light heart.
现在竟然因为小Sholto而入狱
But to be lagged over this young Sholto,
真令人心痛
cursed heart.
如果你能向我句句属实
You must make a clean breast of it
我还能帮你的忙
if you do I may be of use to you.
真像是一家人团圆
Quite a family party.
我想这瓶酒该留给我自己
I reckon I'll pull that flask myself.
好了 你准备去哪儿 Small?
Now, where are you going Small?
Gravesend的Esmeralda
The Esmeralda, at Gravesend,
转道去巴西
outward bound for the Brazils.
几乎就成功了
And nearly made it.
如果当时还有别人驾驶的话
Another man at the engines
你们永远都追不上我们
and you'd never have caught us.
钥匙在哪?
Where's the key my man?
河底
At the bottom of the river.
瞧
Now look here,
今天你给我们带来了不少麻烦 Small
we've had enough of you tonight Small.
把手铐带进来 我警告你
Bring the cuffs in men, I'm warning you.
没事了 警官
Its alright constable
不必拿手铐来了
When we leave the stacks.
我建议我们回贝克街
I suggest that we go back to Baker Street.
我想Morstan小姐在那
Well I think Miss Morstan should be there.
这不合乎规矩 福尔摩斯先生
Well that's not the regulation way Mr. Holmes.
至少我可以请你喝上一杯
Well I can at least promise you a nice,
温暖又美味
warming drink.
很好 各位
Very well gentlemen.
Morstan小姐
Well Miss Morstan
我很荣幸能将
I am pleased and proud
这个贼绳之以法
to have been able to bring the thief to justice.
正义!
Justice?
多好听的正义啊
The pretty justice.
这财宝不是我们的 还能属于谁?
Who's loot is this if it is not ours?
财宝不是他们的 却偏要给他们
Where is the justice that I should give it up
这就是正义?
to those who have never owned it?
你忘记了 Small
You forget Small
他们一无所知
they know nothing of this matter.
判断不出
We cannot tell how far justice
正义是否在你一边
may have originally been on your side.
对 先生
No sir.
您说话还算公道
You have been fair spoken to me,
虽然说我该感谢你
though I can say that it's you
给我的双手
that I have to thank
戴上了手铐
for these bracelets on my wrists.
可我并不怨恨
Still I bear no grudge for that.
要是您想听我的故事
If you want to hear my story
我不会隐瞒
I have no wish to hold it back.
我所说之言
And what I say to you is God's truth,
句句都是真话
every word of it.
当我还是个小伙子
When I was a lad
参军当了兵
I took the Queen's shilling and was
跟随步兵三团去了印度
posted out to India with the Third Buff's.
当我在恒河里游泳的时候
A crocodile snapped this off
一只鳄鱼咬掉了我的腿
when I was bathing in the Ganges.
那畜生像做外科手术一样 干脆地咬掉了我这只腿
The sawbones had my stump
in the tar barrel nice and quick.
我那时还年盛体强
I was young and strong.
我奉命退伍
We got my discharge and this fellow...
而这个家伙....支撑着我
it's been a good support to me
于是我20岁就成了瘸子
so there I was a cripple at 20.
但是我喜欢那里
But I liked it out there
我在那找了一个监工的工作
so I found myself a job as an overseer
在一个经营靛青的农场里
on an Indigo farm.
我每天都骑在马背上 所以境遇还不错
I was on horseback all day so that was fine.
但是好景不长
But I was never in luck for long,
事前没有一点征兆
without a note of warning
大叛乱爆发了
the great mutiny was on us.
一天晚上我回到农场
I came back to the farm one evening to find
发现我的雇主和所有的人都被杀了
my master and all his family be murdered.
我没有等待
I didn't wait.
连夜跑到Agra城
On that same evening I was in the Fort of Agra,
那是英国人控制着的最近的城市
the nearest city still held by the British.
古老的Agra城
The old Fort of Agra,
一个古怪的地方
a queer place,
很大
huge,
到处都是通道和房间
it's full of passages and rooms
更多的是出口 数也数不过来
and more entrances than you can count.
有很多的门
There were many gates
由于我是一个退伍兵  还是英国人
and because I was an ex-soldier and British
他们让我当了一个头目
they put me in charge of one of them
还给我派了几个印度人
and gave me a couple of Sikkhs
他们对我们很忠诚
这是个偏僻的地方
who'd stayed loyal to us.
It was a lonely place.
我手下的两个旁遮普人久经沙场
My 2 Punjabis were experienced, fighting men.
Kartar Singh和Indigo Singh
Kartar Singh and Indigo Singh.
是叛军吗?
Rebels?
不是
No rebels.
堡垒很安全
The fort is safe.
河这边没有叛军士兵
There are no rebel this side of the river.
你要不和我们合作
You must be with us
要不永远沉默
or you must be silenced forever.
和你们合作干什么?
With you how?
我们让你发财
We want you to be rich,
不就是你们英国人来这的目的吗
which is why you British came to this land.
我没理由拒绝发财
Well I have no objection of being rich.
以你父亲的身体发誓
Then swear by the bones of your father
今后绝不做不利于我们的事
to raise no hand
也不说不利于我们的话
and to speak no word against us now
永远都不
or ever afterwards
你会拥有财宝的四分之一
then you will have quarter of the treasure.
但我们只有3个人
But there are only 3 of us.
Jagodish Singh 我的同胞兄弟
Jagodish Singh my foster brother
他也有一份
he must have his share.
没时间了 先生 决定吧
There is no time Sahib decide.
好
Well
如果没有威胁到堡垒的安全
provided the fort is in no kind of danger
我发誓
I swear.
你会怎么做 福尔摩斯先生?
What would you have done Mr. Holmes?
我非常怀疑
I strongly suspect
我和你完全一样
I would have done exactly as you did.
我了解锡克人
Yes I know the Sikkh.
唬弄不了的人
He's not a man to be trifled with.
我们那里的一个首长
One of our local Rajahs,
很有钱
Rich as Croesus of course,
他投靠了叛军
he'd gone in with the rebels.
但是 他害怕万一英军再反扑回来
But... He wanted to hedge his bet
又留了后路
just in case the British came out on top.
他想出个办法 把财产分成2部分
So he made a plot to get half his treasure
藏在Agra城里
hidden in the Fort of Agra
派他手下的人
sending one of his men with it
乔装成商人的样子
in the guise of a merchant
请Jagodish Singh
and Jagodish Singh
就是Kartar的哥哥
Kartar's brother
来做向导
to be the guide.
他们冒着风险来
They come challenging sahib, in a major way
按照惯例问他 别吓着他
giving no caution to fear.
下一步怎么办?
What then?
我们都安排好了
we do what has to be done.
谁?
Who goes there?
自己人 阁下
A friend sahib.
先验清楚
A friend advance and be recognized.
你拿的是什么?
What have you with you?
一个箱子 先生 旧箱子
A box sahib, old box.
一些祖传的东西
Having some family papers.
别人拿着不值钱 自己留着
No good to nobody sahib only for myself.
长官 我不是讨饭的穷人
Sahib, I'm no ordinary beggar.
我会报答你的 先生
You will have money sahib.
还有你的同志们
and you comrades sahib also.
把他带到总部去
Take him to the main guardroom.
他就这样被死神紧紧包围着
Never was a man more compassed round with death.
要是他逃跑
If that man had escaped
整个事情都会败露
the whole affair would have come out.
我会被枪决的
I should have been shot most like.
当时的情况下 你们哪个不会这么做?
Which of you would have held back his musket?
Kartar要火化他
Kartar was for burning him,
那是他们的宗教信仰
that's there religion.
但是点火是不可能的
But such a fire was impossible.
Jagodish要把他扔进
Jagodish was for throwing him down
堡垒下的深沟里
into the great ditch below the fort
下面的柴狗会把他吃干净
where the jackal's to clean him.
毫无疑问他是对的
No doubt he was right.
我一向对死亡有些许的敬意
I'm always for showing some respect for the dead.
接着我们打开箱子
Then we turned to the box,
这个箱子
this box.
里面的珍宝
Inside were more gems
我做梦都想不到
than I could have ever even had dreamed of.
143颗上等钻石
A 1 43 diamonds of the first order
其中一颗叫做"大莫卧儿"
including the Great Mogul,
世界上第二大钻石
the second largest stone in existence.
97块翡翠
97 emeralds,
170块红宝石
1 70 rubies,
40块红玉
40 carbuncles,
61块玛瑙
61 agates.
Jagodish是对的
Jagodish was right,
你们这么把他埋了是错误的
it was a great mistake you made
burying the body as you did
你说是吗 华生?
would you not say so Watson?
确实
Yes indeed.
尸体在印度没被火化的话
Bodies not burned in India
不久就会被发现
are soon discovered.
于是你和你的三个同谋
So you and your 3 companions
被起诉有罪 被叛终身监禁
were found guilty and sent away for life
在安达曼群岛
to the penal colony in the Andaman Islands.
布莱尔岛
Blair Island sir.
希望之城
Hopetown,
没有什么地方的名字比那儿更糟了
never was a place worse named.
那是一个苦力之地
It was a place to sweat.
一个腐朽之地
A place to rot.
一个死亡之地
A place to die.
我在那里年复一年的做劳力
And I sweated there year after year
直到你父亲的到来  Morstan小姐
until your father arrived Miss. Morstan.
下士!
corporal!
你不能虐待白人囚犯
you will not maltreat the white prisoner.
要是再有一次 你就等着受罚吧
If it happens again
you'll be court marshaled.
他是我们的行政长官
He was our administrative officer and he gave me
他在诊疗所给了我一个简易的小屋
a nice cushy villa in the dispensary.
他是我曾经遇到的
He was as good and kind a Christian gentleman
最善良基督信徒了
as I ever come across
我对他没有半点怨恨
and I hold no grudge against him.
你也是 小姐
Or you Miss.
谢谢 Small先生
Thank you Mr. Small.
我坐在这儿 想那些财宝的时候
Well as I sat thinking about the treasure
我仿佛看见那所有的长官
I could see all the offices and the prison officials
喝酒 赌博的场景
at their drinking and their gambling.
Sholto少校从来运气都不好
Major Sholto never had much luck.
每晚他都输
Night after night he was the loser.
有些人天生如此
Some people are born like that.
我输光了 Morstan
It's all over for me Morstan.
我完了
I'm ruined.
我得辞职了
I shall have to send in my paper.
我想你没法再弄到几百块了?
I don't suppose you could manage
我有自己的烦恼
another couple of hundred hey?
I had a pretty nasty face in myself
我有个女儿要抚养
and I have a daughter back home to support.
我也有两个儿子要养活
Well I've got 2 wretched sons.
完蛋了
Ruined hey, damn pity.
所以你决定要接近你的恩人Morstan上尉?
So you decided to approach your benefactor
他经常在诊疗所里
Captain Morstan?
He was often in the dispensary.
热带的气候不适合他
The tropical climate didn't agree with him.
他心脏很弱
His heart was weak
全身血液中毒
and his blood was all poisoned.
知道他会把他所有的安排 都告诉了他的朋友Sholto少校?
Knowing that he would wish to share
any arrangement with his friend
the officer in command, Major Sholto?
是的 那看上去是最安全的方式
Yes sir it seemed the safest way.
这是你个人的私事
And is there any private concern over which
你当然有权按你的方式来处理它们
of course you have the power of disposing
as you think best
谢谢你的忠告
Thank you for that advice sir.
非常感谢
Thank you indeed
但事实是
but the fact is
我在这种环境下
being in the position I am
我需要帮助
I need help.
哪种帮助
What sort of help?
我要一个同伴
I need a partner.
我想Sholto少校和我可以帮助你
Well I'm sure Major Sholto and myself
would like to help you if we could.
至少我们可以谈谈
We could at least talk about,
要是我们同意
that is of course if we can agree as to terms.
在这样的处境下 我只有一个条件
There's only one bargain
a man in my position can make.
恢复我的自由
In exchange for my freedom
还有我那三个同伴
and that of my 3 companions
我们会将宝物的五分之一分给你们
we shall give you a fifth share
五分之一?
to divide between you.
那可不多啊
A fifth?
至少五万英镑
That isn't very much.
50 thousand at the least.
可我们怎么恢复你们的自由呢?
Anyway how can we possibly
你要知道 这不可能
give you your freedom?
我们要的就是一只船和足够的食物
You know it's impossible.
All we need is a boat and provisions.
在Calcutta或是Madras
There are plenty little yachts and yawls
有很多的小快艇
in Calcutta or Madras,
这些就够了
Well enough to serve our purpose.
要是你一个人还好办
If only there were just one of you.
不行
None.
少一个也不行
None or all.
我们发过誓
We have sworn it.
四个人要在一起!
The 4 of us must always act together!
冷静 Sholto
Calm yourself Sholto.
冷静 想想看
Calm yourself,
想想看
think about it man,
Small是一个守信用的人
think about it.
Small is a man of his word
他不辜负朋友
he will not abandon his friends.
我想我们可以信任他
I think we may very well trust him.
我们第二天的凌晨见了面
We met the next morning in the small hours.
我详细写下了我们的协议
I had our written agreement in every detail.
作为大英维多利亚女王领导下军队的长官...
We being officers in the Army
of her majesty Queen Victoria...
在神圣的圣经面前发誓
Do swear on the Holy Bible
永远遵守协议
that this agreement will always remain
永不反悔
sacred and binding to us.
在神圣的圣经面前发誓
Do swear on the Holy Bible
永远遵守协议 永不反悔
that this agreement will always remain
sacred and binding to us.
我给他们每个人一张地图
I gave each of them a plan
标出了宝藏的位置
showing the position of the treasure.
这个把我的记忆带回到那时
Oh that brings back memories.
Sholto坐船去了印度
Sholto took the next boat to India,
找到了宝藏
found the treasure
把宝藏带回了英国?
and took it back with him to England?
是的
Yes.
当我们听到消息
When we heard the news
Morstan上尉和我都很气愤
Captain Morstan was as angry as I was.
他向我发誓
He swore to me he would go home
要回去找Sholto算账
and settle the matter with Sholto.
要是他还活着 他会的
And so he would if he lived
但是那不可能了
but that was not to be.
从那天起
From that day,
我只为报仇而活
I lived only for vengeance.
日夜不忘
I thought of it by day,
I nursed it by night
要找到Sholto
to get to Sholto,
亲手掐住他的喉咙
put my hands on his throat
那就是我唯一的想法
that was my one thought.
幸运的是
As luck would have it,
岛上的一个居民 被带到了我的医疗所
one of the islanders
被蛇咬伤 大半条命已经没了
had been brought in to my dispensary,
more than half dead from a snakebite.
出于人道 我尽所能帮助他
And in common humanity I did my best for him.
于是他康复过来
Somehow he pulled through
变得对我非常忠诚
and became very devoted to me,
一个有趣的小矮子
a funny little fellow.
先生们
Well you gentlemen
你们见过他
caught a glimpse of him yourselves,
毫无疑问 就在昨晚
no doubt, last night.
他就是忠诚可靠的小Tonga
He was staunch and true little Tonga.
没有比他更忠诚的同伴了
No man ever had a more faithful mate.
他是个渔夫
Being by trade a fisherman
有一只不错的土著船
he had a goodish size native boat
他同意和我一起逃走
and he had agreed to try to escape with me.
10天之后 我们遇见了一只商船
After 1 0 days we were picked up by a trader
带着一批香客 从马来开往吉达
with a cargo of pilgrims from Malay bound for Gito.
数月之后
After many months
我们历经艰险
we worked our way across the world
回到了伦敦
to London.
过程很精彩
A remarkable account.
现在 我想Morstan小姐
And now I think Miss Morstan
可能想看看这些财宝
might like to see the Great Agra Treasure,
这将使她成为全英国最有钱的女士之一
which will surely make her
-华生? -没钥匙
one of the richest young ladies in England.
我想这跟铁火棍可以
Watson?
There's no key.
I'm sure our iron poker will oblige.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha
这是你做的 Small?
This is your doing Small.
是的
Yes.
我把宝藏都扔掉了
Yes I put the treasure away
你们永远也得不到
where you shall never lay a hand on it.
没有人能有权利拥有
No living man or woman has any right to it
除非是在安达曼兵营里的那三个人 还有我
unless it is the 3 men
in the Andaman Convict Barracks and myself.
我知道我没机会拥有了
I know now that I cannot have the use of it,
没人会有
no more can they.
我做的这些是为了他们 也是为我
But I have acted all along
for them as much as for myself.
我们一直把四签名带在身上
We have the sign of four with us always.
宝藏哪去了?
Where is it?
在钥匙所在的地方
Where the key is
在小Tonga所在的地方
and where little Tonga is.
我看见你们的汽艇要赶上我们
I saw your launch might catch us
我看小Tonga倒在一边
and I saw little Tonga go over the side.
我把财宝放到了一个安全的地方
I put the loot in a safe place.
你骗我们 Small
You are deceiving us Small if you had wished
要是你想把财宝扔进泰晤士河
to throw the treasure into the Thames
把箱子扔进去不是更容易
it would have been easier
我扔得容易
to have thrown box and all.
你们捞得也容易
Easier for me to throw
and easier for you to recover.
有本事把我抓住的人
A man who's clever enough to hunt me down
也有本事把箱子
is clever enough to pick up a box
从河底捞上来
from the bottom of the river.
我很遗憾
I am sorry.
我很庆幸财宝没了
I am glad the treasure is lost.
对于拥有宝藏的人来说 它只是个诅咒
It's been nothing but a curse
to every man who has owned it.
不仅是我可怜的父亲
And only death to my poor father.
还有我和我同伴们苦役的生活
And slavery for life
to me and my companions.
我们的前半生都
We spent the first half of my life
在Andaman修水坝
digging a breakwater in the Andaman's.
可能我的下半生要在
And I'm likely to spend the other half
Dartmoor修水渠了
digging ditches on Dartmoor.
福尔摩斯 责任就是责任
Well Holmes duty is duty
今天对你已经够通融了
and I've gone rather far in bringing him here.
我相信只有把这个讲故事的人送进监狱
I shall feel more at ease
我才能放心
when I have our storyteller here
我很感谢你们的协助
under lock and key.
I am obliged to you for your assistance.
再见 华生医生
Good day to you. Doctor Watson,
Morstan小姐
Miss Morstan.
你先走 Small
Awe, after you Small.
否则你要用木腿打我真是太容易了
you seem a bit handy
with that wooden leg of yours.
真是惭愧 福尔摩斯先生
I feel most ashamed that you Mr. Holmes
还有亲爱的华生医生
and you dear Doctor Watson
让你们为了我的事
have had to put yourself
冒了那么多的险
into such peril on my behalf.
一切都结束了 别这么说
Oh that's all over and forgotten.
Forrester夫人派他的车夫 来接Morstan小姐了
Mrs. Forrester has sent her carriage for Miss Morstan.
我不会再给你们添麻烦了 两位
I'll impose on you no longer gentlemen.
你们一定筋疲力尽了
You must be exhausted.
我承认这次行动消耗了太多精力
Yes I confess the reaction is already upon me.
我这一个星期都会软绵绵的
I shall be as limp as a rag for a week.
我很感谢您洗刷了我父亲的名声
I'm so very grateful to you
for clearing my father's name.
也很感激您
I'm so very grateful to you both.
好像不太公平
Seems so unfair.
这个案子里都是你在做事
You ve done all the work in this business
Athelney Jones却赢得了名声
and Athelney Jones gets all the credit.
你得到了什么?
What remains for you?
对于我 我得到了解决 一件有趣案子的快乐
For me, the pleasure of having solved
几乎是独自一人完成的
an interesting case almost single-handed.
对于你 毫无疑问
And for you no doubt the pleasure
得到了把故事写下来的快乐
以你那种通俗的浪漫的形式
of writing it up
in your usual flowery and romantic style.
多迷人的女人
What a very attractive woman.
她吗?
Was she?
我没注意
I hadn't noticed.
风软FRM字幕组作品 -==http://www.1000fr.com==- 欢迎加入